RAJESWARI BESTA

Result-driven professional with proven Human Resource and Administration experience. Accomplished in determining most optimal HR practices, achieving all objectives and ensuring smooth operations.

- ☐ Al Attar Tower, DIFC, Dubai, UAE
- □ **Mob No.:** 058-191-0657
- ☐ **WhatsApp**: 056-878-2161

EDUCATION

- MBA (HR & Marketing) GNTU, IND in 2010.
- B.Sc SK University, IND in 2008.

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

- HR Versatile Award.
- Best HR Excellence Award.
- HR Quick Learner Award.
- 3 times frequent Appraisals.

MISCELLANEOUS ACHIEVEMENTS

 Joined in NCC and received "A" Certificate with "B" Grade.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Microsoft Office Suite, including Word, Outlook, Excel, and PowerPoint
- HRMS & ERP Software

LANGUAGES

 English, Telugu, Kannada, Hindi & Tamil

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Looking for a suitable position where I can use the skills that I have acquired and also to be a member of a growing organization that provides an opportunity to enhance my skills with recognition.

SUMMARY

A multi-skilled professional with good all-round HR advisory skills. Very capable with an ability deal with all the recruitment and resourcing needs of an organization. Experienced in providing timely and up to date HR advice to both managers and employees whilst at the same time making sure both the employee and employers interests are best represented. Extensive knowledge of working practices, recruitment, pay, conditions of employment and diversity issues.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

End-End Recruitment	Training & Development	Visa Process
Medical Insurances	Payroll Functions	Compensation & Benefits
HR Policies & Procedures	Employee Relations & Retention	Employee Engagement
MIS Report, KPI, Ratios	General Administrations	HRIS Technologies
UAE Labor Laws	Portals Access (like GDRFA, MOL, E-Dirham & so on)	Grievance Handling
Leave generations system	Files Management	Exit Interviews

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nov 2015- Jan 2020 Sr HR Executive

ORYX BOLD GROUP

Sep 2013- Nov 2015 Human Resources Recruiter

ARTECH INFO SYSTEMS

Feb 2011- Oct 2013 HR Team Lead

BRIDGE HR CONSULTING PVT LTD

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for managing all HR operations and strategies within the company.
- Maintain employees' personnel files and records.
- Modernize organizational/departments chart.
- Customize work structure by updating job requirement and job specs for each position.
- Implantation of policies, procedures & grading structure.
- Process of all new hires, benefits orientations, termination and payroll paperwork ensuring compliance with applicable laws & regulatory mandates.
- Issuing of all staff offer letters and increments as per authority matrix.
- Responsible for prepare & process of Office Memos
- Thorough experience on preparing Offer Letters, Joining formalities, Duty Resume, Warning, Suspension / Termination, Salary and all other Letters & Memos.
- Transfer of staff internally.
- Evaluation of new staff before completion of probation period, in coordination with Department Managers.

PERSONAL DETAILS

- DOB: May 01,1987
- Marital Status: Single
- Father Name: Ravindra B
- Nationality: Indian
- Passport No.:M8646344
- Visa Status: Residence Visa

- Maintain & update salary scale as per market rate, YEARLY with coordination with Head of HRD.
- Implantation of induction programs for staff.
- Career path for employees.
- Tracking attendance, maintaining leave records & other payroll related records.
- Responsible for entire payroll process.
- Bonus distribution with coordination with Head of HRD.
- Monitoring and maintaining office equipment, inventory supplies; orders replacement supplies as needed
- Monthly salary calculation including allowance (e.g. overtime, transportation).
- Prepare summary sheets (e.g. Telephone and Utilities personal charges).
- Processing various expense reimbursements, allowance or subsidy application form
- Deductions (e.g. personal charge and loan)
- Updating employee salary changes as informed and approved by the HQ or General Manager

Recruitment:

- Resourcing, screening and shortlisting CVs through various job portals, referrals, headhunting, job postings, bulk mails, SMS & so on.
- Shortlisting CVs based on the jobrequirements.
- Conducting telephonic and F2F interviews and proceed with the HR Head & Department Heads.
- Preparing job offer, employment contract and job descriptions, completing joining Formalities and documentations.

Training & Development:

- Identification of training needs and nominating staff for training.
- Conduct training program & collecting feedback.
- Issuing training certificates after completion of the training.

Public Relation:

- Deal promptly and productively on general enquiries about PRO functions.
- Knowledge and experience on the portal system usage (Immigration, MOL, E- dirham, Noqodi & so on)
- Proficient typing skills in English.
- Coordinate with PRO in order to submit correct documents to the MOL for all type of visas.
- Experience on entire visa process (New, Renewal & Cancellation).
- Renew, update and keep up all workers and their dependents' visas and work contracts on time to guarantee that organization's records are up to date in the labor and Immigration Departments. Send notification to employees on required documents before their visa expires
- All business and trade Licenses are updated, follow-up official approvals and permits, to prevent unnecessary violations.
- Arrange medical tests, passports, promotional draws and fine/overstay resolution.
- Coordinate with the employees for the exit/status change procedure.

Exit Formalities:

- Conducting the Exit interview for Generating feedback on the Organization's performance and areas of improvement.
- Generating Relieving, -Experience Letters and salary certificates.
- Preparation of final settlements, no due clearance relating to employees
- Conducting exit formalities and updating employee's attrition list of the organization.
- Maintaining and updating database of exit employees.